## Personal Information

Address: 1599A 39th Street

Los Alamos, NM 87544 Phone: +1 (920) 858-8783

Email: casey.alan.anderson@gmail.com

# CASEY A. ANDERSON

https://www.linkedin.com/in/caseyalananderson

Work Information

Address: P.O. Box 1663

Los Alamos, NM 87545 Phone: +1 (505) 667-5968

Email: casey\_a@lanl.gov

# **Executive Summary**

**Nuclear engineer**, **physicist**, and **programmer** with over six years of experience involving scientific computing, critical thinking, and analytical problem solving. Leader in student organizations, strong collaborator in diverse work environments, demonstrated history meeting deliverables and communicating results.

"Put in a quote right here from someone, and its okay if it goes over a few lines thats okay" Quote Person

# **Professional Experience**

# Los Alamos National Laboratory

Los Alamos, New Mexico

Graduate Research Assistant Graduate Research Assistant Post Master's Research Assistant Summer Intern

NEN-5, Systems Design & Analysis<sup>1</sup>
ISR-1, Space Science & Applications<sup>2</sup>
W-13, Advanced Engineering Analysis<sup>3</sup>
XCP-3, Monte Carlo Codes<sup>4</sup>

May 2016 - Present Dec. 2016 - Present May 2011 - Jul. 2012

2010

- Implemented new features in MCNP6 through writing code, developing benchmarks, publishing reports, and presenting the new features at various conferences [Pubs: 1,2,4,5,6]<sup>1</sup>
- Gained significant knowledge and experience in the design, modeling, simulation, and analysis of a variety of radiation detectors for the Nuclear Detection Figure of Merit (NDFOM) project<sup>2</sup>
- Transitioned NDFOM from version 2.0 to 3.0 by modularizing and refactoring the backend Python code and through developing a cleaner, more intuiative HTML user interface for the customer<sup>2</sup>
- Managed the deployed server of NDFOM, including SQL database<sup>2</sup>
- Assisted in the development, testing, validation, and verification of the combined radiation transport and finite-element analysis multi-physics capability for the **Engineering Campaign-7 Nuclear Survivability** project<sup>3</sup>
- Developed unstructured mesh human phantoms for health physics applications with MCNP6 [Pub: 10]<sup>3</sup>
- Acquired DOE Q-level security clearance and Sigmas 1-10,11,12,13,15 and performed analysis on the W-88 system<sup>3</sup>
- Utilized the high performance computing (HPC) systems and utilities for advanced physics simulations and analysis<sup>1,2,3,4</sup>
- Created a software visualization package for finite element geometries in MCNP simulations<sup>4</sup>

## Medical College of Wisconsin

Milwaukee, Wisconsin

Graduate Research Assistant Department of Biophysics 2012-2016<sup>1</sup>
Biophysics Representative, IT Liason Graduate Student Council 2014-2016<sup>2</sup>

- Funded my graduate studies through conducting the background research, providing the preliminary results, and co-authoring a successful R21 National Institute of Health (NIH) grant<sup>1</sup>
- Patented a segmented reconstruction technique for artifact reduction in Magnetic Resonance Imaging [Pat: i.]
- Collaborated with a diverse group of professionals, including medical doctors and imaging technologists, to perform clinical research, meet deliverables, and submit the findings to various international conferences [Pubs: 7,8,9]<sup>1</sup>
- Interacted with clinical patients and subjects to collect patient data for clinical studies
- Facilitated communication between students and staff in the graduate school with the university's Information Technology group<sup>2</sup>

## University of Wisconsin - Madison

Madison, Wisconsin

Student Research Assistant Department of Medical Physics 2008-2011
Chapter President American Nuclear Society (ANS) 2010-2011

- · Researched methods for non-invasive quality assurance assessment of radioactive brachytherapy seeds
- Managed the American Nuclear Society organizational duties, including activities such as recruiting guest speakers to present at meetings, organizing conference travel, and arranging public outreach events
- Mentored an taught a variety of students through volunteering at various events, such as Science Olympiad, middle
  and high school science fairs, and teaching local Boy Scout chapters to achieve their merit badges

# Areas of Expertise

# Physics/Engineering

- Nuclear Engineering
- Fourier Analysis
- Monte Carlo Methods
- Magnetic Resonance Imaging
- High Performance Computing
- Signal Processing
- Regularization Methods
- Radiation Detectors
- Multi-physics coupling
- Radioactive Material Handling
- O Computer Aided Engineering
- O Finite Element Analysis

## Software

- MCNP
- Abaqus/CAE
- Linux
- Matplotlib
- Microsoft Office
- Matlab
- MacOS
- PostgreSQL
- Windows
- VisIt
- O RELAP

# **Programming**

- Python
- Bash
- IATEX
- Unit Testing
- Matlab
- Mercurial
- Git
- **○** C/C++
- Fortran
- Debugging
- Java

# Other Skills

- Technical Writing
- Presentations
- Leadership
- Version Control
- File I/O
- Scripting
- Data Visualization
- Validation & Verification
- SQL Databases
- Clinical Work
- Server Management
- Animal Handling

#### **Key** (Skill Level)

• Expert • Intermediate ○ Beginner

# **Funding Sources**

General Electric / National Football League concussion study grant MCW
Department of Homeland Security (DHS) / Department of Nuclear Detection Office (DNDO)
Department of Homeland Security (DHS) / Nuclear Detection Figure-of-Merit (NDFOM)
Engineering Campaign 7, Nuclear Survivability
W-13

## **Awards & Honors**

SPOT Award Los Alamos National Laboratory August, 2017
Magna Cum Laude ISMRM Proceeding May, 2016
Silver Medal: Student Poster ISMRM Conference 2014
Exelon Scholarship University of Wisconsin - Madison 2009, 2010

# **Afilliations**

American Nuclear Society (ANS) 2008-2012, 2016-Present
American Association of Physicists in Medicine (AAPM) 2009-2011, 2013-2016
International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine (ISMRM) 2012-2016

# Education

## **Primary Education**

M. Sc, Biophysics Medical College of Wisconsin April, 2016
M. Sc, Nuclear Engineering & Engineering Physics University of Wisconsin - Madison Hay, 2011
B. Sc, Nuclear Engineering University of Wisconsin - Madison Hay, 2011

Thesis: "Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping: Exploratory Development and Initiation of Processing Pipelines"

## **Additional Classes & Trainings**

MCNP6 Intermediate Workshop Los Alamos New Mexico May, 2016 **CPR Certification Training** Milwaukee, Wisconsin May, 2015 General Electric MR Programming Workshop Madison, Wisconsin Oct, 2014 **Dale Carnegie Training** Los Alamos, New Mexico August, 2011 **Introduction to Abaqus** Minneapolis, Minnesota June, 2011 Introduction to Python Programming Los Alamos, New Mexico July, 2010 MCNP5 Beginner Workshop Los Alamos, New Mexico May, 2010

#### References

A list of professional, academic, and personal references can be at here

#### **Publications & Presentations**

- 1. Casey Anderson and Gregg McKinney. "MCNP6 Built-in High Level Detector Responses". In: 2017 IEEE Nuclear Science Symposium and Medical Imaging Conference. (Atlanta, Georgia). Oct. 2017,
- 2. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson et al. "Neutron and Gamma Correlations using CGM in MCNP 6.2.0 (LA-UR-20353)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting.* (San Fransisco, California). 2017, Link
- 3. § James Tutt and Gregg McKinney. "Speed and Memory Improvements to MCNP6 Delayed-Gamma Line Treatment (LA-UR-21050)". In: *Proceedings of the 27th American Nuclear Society Summer Meeting*. (San Fransisco, California). 2017
- 4. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson et al. "Delta-ray production in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-25402)". In: *24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry*. (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016, Link
- 5. <sup>‡</sup> James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Background-Source Cosmic-Photon Elevation Scaling and Cosmic-Neutron/Photon Date Scaling in MCNP6 (LA-UR-16-24928)". In: 24th Conference on Applications of Accelerators in Research and Industry. (Forth Worth, Texas). Nov. 2016, Link
- 6. James Tutt, Casey Anderson, and Gregg McKinney. "Delayed-Gamma Energy Biasing with Exact Energy Sampling in MCNP6.2.0 (LA-UR-16-24057)". In: *Proceedings of the 26th American Nuclear Society Winter Meeting*. (Las Vegas, Nevada). Oct. 2016, Link
- 7. Casey Anderson et al. "Volume-Paracellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping". In: Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 24th Conference. (Singapore, Singapore). May 2016, Link
- 8. † Casey Anderson and Kevin Koch. "Volume-parcellated Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping of the Human Brain at 7T". in: 2015 Minnesota Workshop on High and Ultra-High Field Imaging. (Minneapolis, Minnesota). Oct. 2015, Link
- 9. Casey Anderson, Kimberley Pechman, and Kathleen Schmainda. "Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping to Assess Iron Levels in Rat Brain Tumors". In: *Proceedings of the International Society of Magnetic Resonance in Medicine 22nd Conference*. (Milan, Italy). May 2014, Link
- 10. <sup>‡</sup> Casey Anderson, Tim Goorley, and Karen Kelley. "Mesh Human Phantoms with MCNP (LA-UR-12-01307)". In: 2012 3DS Simulia Community Conferece Proceedings. (Providence, Rhode Island). May 2012, pp. 556–568, Link

‡Presentation Included; §Presentation Only; | Magna Cum Laude

#### **Patents**

i. Kevin Koch and Casey Anderson. System and method for localized processing of quantitative susceptibility maps in magnetic resonance imaging. WO Patent App. PCT/US2016/038,723. Dec. 2016. URL: https://www.google.com/ patents/W02016209930A1?cl=en, Link